なぜだ
Why?
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
Why are you here?
なぜ　お前がここにいる
お…お前のような小僧の首はいらん
M-I do not want your head!
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
Where Prince Arslan ?!
アルスラーン王子はどこだ
私が　アルスラーンだ
I
Lion.
Y-you tricked me!
謀ったな
I'll take your head!
その首　もらい受ける
Elam!
エラム
Prince...
殿下…
otoydite.
お下がりください
kaze ga zawameki kudaketa kimochi
Quiet wind awakens emotions and broken,
日听&翻译
小伍
大脸猫
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
misukashi teru you de furueta yo
I see through everything and I shiver.
michita tsuki no hi touboe no inochi
In the sky a full moon, and the city comes howling:
片源
Rei
时间轴
蛛蛛&雪糕
压制
Coolkid
mada oite kanaide yo
"Please do not throw until we have!"
bokura torikaeseru ka na iro tsuki no sora
Will we return to the old sky, painted in the colors?
hokori mamire no yume mai agete
Rise in the dance vortex hourglass Sci,
kobushi wo nigittanara
to be clamped in their fists.
ima hashire hashire tsuji kaze ni natte
Now run forward, run forward, and stand by the whirlwind,
rettou zetsubou issai fukitobashite iku
feelings of hopelessness and despair of sour cream on the way.
oikakenakya saigo no tobira
Clears the currently last track.
nando chittatte dai gyakuten
Let all break, we will rise again,
kono goe ga shagare tatte inorinouta todoketai yo
even a hoarse voice will sing songs and prayers.
tarinai bokura de shinji teta sekai wo ubaetara
Even insignificant, as we will be able to capture the whole world in which to believe.
madamada madamada make rarenai
We have still not yet been defeated!
Chapter XXIV
Elam!
エラム
It is commendable that you have found this place.
うまくこの場所を見つけたものだ
だが…
But...
Narsus!
ナルサス
The invasion failed.
突撃は失敗じゃな
Would you agree to give up ...?
降伏してはくれぬか
Gentiles ...
異教徒め
Captain, we will not hold them anymore!
隊長　もうもちません
Retreat!
お退きください
No!
ダメだ
Who will protect the graph Barkasiona, if not you ?!
あなた以外に　誰がバルカシオン伯爵を守るのです
Stand!
お待ち
You will not go away!
逃がさないよ
Alfrid!
アルフリード
Given that the castle is surrounded by,
城が包囲されている以上
they must have a hidden passage there.
あの者らが通ってきた隠し通路があるはずだ
I got it!
分かったよ
Elam!
エラム
Somebody help Elam!
誰か　早くエラムを
Bad.
いかんな
I'm sorry that in such an important moment ...
申し訳ありません　肝心なときに…
Do not speak.
しゃべらなくていい
I do not remember to educate you so reckless.
こんなむちゃをするようにしつけた覚えはないはずだが
I have proved their benefit?
お役に立てましたか
Yes.
ああ
エラム…
Elam ...
Prince, do not look at me like that.
殿下　そんな顔をしないでください…
You are the person who should take the throne.
仮にも国王となろうとしている方が
You must be persistent and strong.
しっかりしていただかないと
Yes you are right.
ああ　そうだな
To him ... to him!
おのれ…　おのれ…
This guy is just a spoiled fooled me to this day!
あの坊ちゃん　今日まで私を謀っていたのか
And I have so many chances ... it was ...
私は何度も機会がありながら…
Every time I missed it ?!
みすみす逃していたのか
Secret passage among the rocks ...
こんな崖の中に抜け道があるなんて
So, it's time to show you what women are terrible clan Zot!
さあ　ゾット族の女の怖さ　教えてあげるよ
Prince!
殿下
Prince.
殿下　襲撃されたとは誠ですか
It is true that attacked the camp?
ダリューン
Darjun.
I'm fine.
私なら大丈夫だ
But Elam hurt protecting me.
だが　エラムが私をかばい　手傷を負ってしまった
Elam?
エラムが…
This was thoughtless invasion for glory.
功を急いた無謀な突撃だった
It looks like the guy temperamental.
あの少年の気性なのだろうな
That guy?
あの少年
Maybe you remember him.
覚えているだろうか
Lyusitanianets, which we released when he took me to the hostages.
かつて私が人質にされたとき
取り逃がしたルシタニアの少年だ
はい
As if ...
あのときと同じく…
Although now his gaze was even worse.
いや　今はそれ以上に険しい瞳をしていた
Prince...
殿下…
Darjun. Narsus.
ダリューン　ナルサス
I also sent.
私も出るぞ
Prince goes into battle?
殿下がご出陣を
If in this battle we are,
戦況が五分だというのなら
Now the king must go ahead
今こそ王が先頭に立ち　皆を励まし　奮い立たせるべきだ
to inspire people and raise their morale.
It is unlikely that I will do so, as her father,
父上のようにはできないだろうが
but for those who suffer in combat,
今日まで傷ついてきた皆のためにも
I want to go into battle!
私は出陣したい
Mr. Narsus!
ナルサス様　アルフリード様より報告です
Report from the Alfred mistress!
Finally.
来たか
She reports that will open the gates at dawn.
夜明けとともに城門を開けるとのことです
Good.
承知した
We are a key element in this battle. So do not hesitate.
私らがこの戦の要　ひるむんじゃないよ
On the day of my first battle of Atropatena,
アトロパテネの初陣の日　私は敗走した
I was defeated.
I was in deep despair,
絶望の淵にあったが
but here today,
今日まで
because with me Daryun, Narsus and my people.
ダリューンや　ナルサスや　そして　ここにいる全ての者が
Thanks to your support.
私を支えてくれた
皆と共にエクバタナを奪還する
Together we will refund Ecbatana,
and then I...
そして　私は皆の王となろう
will your King!
Castle Defense is strong.
城の守りは強固だ
But now
だが今　味方の決死隊が敵の隠し道から侵入し
we boldly go through a secret passage to the enemy
and with the coming of dawn break through the gates!
夜明けとともに門を破る
Parsis gods!
パルスの神々よ　あまたの英霊たちよ
And the souls of our fallen heroes!
I ask you, provide us with support in this battle!
願わくば　我らにお力を貸したまえ
Jasasuiin!
ヤシャスィーン
Go.
来たぞ
いけ
Forward!
いくよ
Hurry! Open the gates before the sun fully rises!
急げ　朝日が昇りきるまでに城門を開けるんだ
こ…こいつら　どこから
Where did they come from?
Do not panic! They are few!
慌てるな　寡兵だ　下の兵を呼んで…
gather the people from below and ...
Support our inside!
突入部隊を援護しろ
Sudden attack on the gates of the castle ?!
城門上に奇襲だと
Send to the people and to repel the attack!
早く兵を回し　鎮圧しろ
There is!
はっ
If they open the gates, and we are not last minute!
門を開かれたら　一刻と　もたんぞ
Mr. Zaravant!
ザラーヴァント様
Gates began to open!
門が開きはじめましたぞ
Why is the gate open?
な…なぜ　城門が開いている
Gather people in a castle!
城の兵を集めよ　門の内側に壁を…
Create a wall at the gate ...
Soon there will be the main army!
すぐに本隊が来るぞ
A bit more! Hold on!
あと少しだ　頑張れ
Pushes them! You can not miss ... more
お…押し返せ　これ以上　中に入れては…
なんだ
To deploy troops on the left and right!
部隊を左右に展開
We come to the castle gate, and pushed the enemy troops!
城門を駆け上がって　敵兵を制圧せよ
The main forces do not stop!
主力部隊は足を止めるな　そのまま本城を落とせ
Rushes and capture the castle!
Narsus!
ナルサス
来ましたな
Come ...
来るぞ　これ以上　進ませるな
Go! Do not pass them on!
ダリューン　キシュワード　遠慮はいらん
Daryun! Kisvard! Do not hold back!
There is!
殿下
Prince!
挟撃
At both sides?!
殿下を守れ
Protect the prince!
あれは
It...
クバード
Kuʙard!
アルスラーン王子　随分とりりしくなられた
Prince Lions!
You are such a valiant warrior steel!
駆けつけた甲斐もあったというもの
I have decided that it is worth to join you!
さあ　行かれよ
Come on, go!
ご自身が真の王だと言われるなら
If you're applying for something to be a real king,
ご自分自身で示さねばなりませぬぞ
you will have to prove it on their own!
抜けたぞ
We burst!
殿下　進みましょう
Prince, come on.
ジャスワント　頼む
Jaswant, please!
はっ
There is!
生きていたら　酒でもおごれよ
If you survive, be sure to buy me wine, Daryun!
ダリューン
見えたぞ
I see!
サームか
Milk powder!
今だ
Now!
行きましょう
Idemte!
Yes!
ナルサス
Narsus!
行け
Go!
立ち止まれば　こやつの隊に包囲されるぞ
If you stop, you will immediately be surrounded!
ナルサス　死ぬなよ
Narsus ...
Do not die!
It will depend on you.
それはお主らしだいだ
イアルダボート神よ…
God Ialdabaoth ...
所詮はギスカールの借り物どもよ　いくら数を減らそうがかまわん
It's like people Giscard.
I do not care how poredeyut their ranks.
むしろルシタニアにとっても程よい痛手となろう
Lyusitaniya suffer heavy losses.
来い　アンドラゴラスの小せがれ
Invoked offspring Andragorasa ...
You suffer a humiliation in front of his subordinates.
貴様は忠臣たちの前に最大の屈辱をさらすことになるのだ
殿下　あとは私が
Prince, I'll deal with the rest.
いや　私が行かねばならない
No, I gotta go.
この先に従兄弟殿がいるのだろう
They were hiding my cousin, right?
ファランギース
Farangis!
With me the divine protection of Mithras.
私にはミスラ神の加護があります
汚れた邪教の矢が私に当たることなどありえませぬ
Arrows of corrupt heretics will not get me!
そして殿下　あなたにも神のご加護があります
And the prince, this divine protection extends to you.
非道な輩に悔い改めさせることができるのは
I believe that you and only you
殿下において他にないと私は思っております
You will be able to send these barbarous people to the true path.
お行きください
Go.
殿下の行く先　敵は全て私が射抜いてさしあげましょう
Wherever you go,
there I was fighting all the enemies with his arrows.
殿下　行きましょう
Prince, let's go!
Yes.
アルスラーン王子か
You're Prince Arslan?
まだ子供ではないか
Still just a kid ...
やはり黒衣の騎士と一緒か
Still came with a black knight, as I waited.
ペシャワールの夜以来になるな　従兄弟殿
Not seen since the night in Peshavarde, dear brother.
従兄弟などと呼ばれるのは汚らわしいが
I hate to hear from your lips the word "brother", but the fellow that came.
よく来た
さぞや　今日ここにたどりつくまでに苦しんだことであろうな
I hope you had suffered a great deal as was getting here,
アルスラーン
Lions!
耳を貸してはなりませぬぞ
Do not pay any attention to him.
いや
No.
私は彼の話が聞きたい
I want to hear it.
殿下…
Prince.
苦悩を乗り越え　私に追いついたとでも思っているのか
Do you think that having overcome all difficulties, you become a match for me?
笑わせるな
You can not!
お前はここで無残に討ち死にし　醜態をさらすことになる
You in this game is waiting for the tragic death and disgrace!
それでも　私が受けた屈辱に足りるものではない
But still,
it does not compare to the humiliation that I have experienced!
私の怒りが収まりはしない
My anger will never end!
貴様はそんな逆恨みで　ずっと殿下を追い詰めていたというのか
Due to some unjustified resentment
you all the while pursued Prince ?!
逆恨みだと
Unjustified insults ?!
この癒えぬ傷の痛み　貴様に分かるものか
You will never understand the pain unhealed wounds!
分かります
I understand.
だが　傷ついているのはあなただけではない
But you do not suffer alone.
パルスの民　皆だ
People Parsis too.
あなたが国を思う正統な血縁だというのなら…
If you are
proclaims itself the true king,
どうだろう　私に力を貸してはくれないだろうか
how do you like this:
if you agree to help me?
王位を譲る…　とは言わぬのだな
So, you are not going to yield to my throne.
今や私にも背負うものがある
At me now the responsibility.
皆の望みと私の望みは同じだ
The desire of the people the same as mine.
サーム様　もうダメです
Mr. Saam, we do not hold out!
ヒルメス殿下…
Prince Hermes ...
退け　退け
Retreat! Retreat!
私がパルスの王を継ぐ
I will be worthy of the king of Parsa!
国と民を思う気持ちはあなたと違いない
My attitude to the kingdom and its people is different from yours!
貴様は
Bastard!
殿下　今の言葉　しかと胸に刻みました
Prince, your words will remain forever in my heart.
ダリューン
Darjun ...
あなたの家臣でよかった
I'm glad to serve you.
貴様ら　どこまで私をイラつかせる
How much you will still pour oil into the fire ?!
不浄の血縁　それに味方する貴様らはパルス騎士の恥さらしよ
He is not a descendant of the royal!
And you bastards, serving him only disgrace the knights Parsis!
殿下を愚弄することは許さん
Do not allow to insult the prince!
ダリューン
Darjun!
バルカシオン伯爵ですね
Count Barkasion, I believe?
さよう
Right.
此度　多くの家臣を失った　戦などつらいことだ
I lost a lot of people in this battle.
War is always cruel.
だから　早く終わらせなければならないのです
Therefore, we should as soon as possible to finish it.
あなたはお優しい王なのかもしれない
Perhaps you will become a good king.
イアルダボート教は他の信徒は認めない
Faith Yaldabaoth not accept other believers.
何百年も変わらなかった
This has not changed for centuries.
果たして方法がありますかなぁ
Is there any other way?
それは…
It...
惜しいな　マルダーン・フ・マルダーン
What a shame, Mardan Mardan fu!
You should have sent its strength at the service of
その力　正統の王のために…
使えばよかったものを
the true King!
断じてありえん　我が王はアルスラーン殿下のみ
It's impossible!
My king - Prince Arslan and more!
信念に突き動かされた忌々しい目だ
Your glare accompanied by confidence.
証明してみせようではないか
Can I show you?
誰が正しいのか
Who do wrong ...
まだ殺さぬ　お前たちが心の底から負けたと思わないかぎりな
I will not kill you.
While you are with all your heart does not acknowledge
that definitively lost.
そうでなければ　意味がない
Otherwise, everything will be useless.
そうでなくては　私の怒りが収まることはないのだ
Otherwise, my rage will never die down!
待て…
Stay! ..
くそ
Heck...
バルカシオン伯爵様
Mr. Barkasion graph ...
It seems that the fall of the castle is already inevitable.
もはや落城は避けられぬようじゃ
降伏…　してはくださいませんか
You agree to give up ...?
無駄に殺すな　我々は文明国であるパルスの民だ
Without useless bloodshed!
We the people Parsis, a civilized country!
略奪もならん　固く命じる
No looting!
That's an order!
やめろ
Stay!
伯爵　戦いは終わった
Graf, the battle is over! Stop them!
皆を止めてくれ
優しい異教の王子よ
Good King of the Gentiles,
だからといって　止められるものではありませぬ
Whatever it was, it did not stop.
信仰とはそういうものです
Such is the nature of the believer.
よせ
Stay!
私にできることは皆と　そして神と共にあることです
I can only
be with the people and our Lord.
なぜだ　せっかく助かる命だというのに
Why?! You do save lives! Why would you want to die ?!
どうして死ななければならない
貴様
Bastard!
やめろ
Stay!
伯爵様を殺したのは　お前か
Did you kill Mr. Earl?
YakuSub Studio
translation Mu_Cool
kimi ga deatta kokoro wa kitto
All the souls that you could meet on the way,
hitotsu datte machigai janai
certainly it was pure and innocent,
Editorial Mu_Cool
onaji yume wo daite
We kept the same dream.
Making Weekend
michi wo tagaeta hito wo omotta
People walking different paths,
nozarashi no akogare wo kakagete susumu kouya
killed all my hopes and desires revive again.
hohoemi mo sono namida mo
Smile on his face, tears running down her cheeks,
koko ni suteteyukenai kara
If you want to go ahead, they should not be forgotten.
kage wo daite shiroku takaku
Covered by the shadow of the summer, so white and immense,
namonaki boku to kimi no hata
our with you nameless flag flies.
mada hatenaku tsudzuku kono mich ino kanata ni
There, on the road, which extends an endless path,
tatta hitotsu no hikari wo sen no kokoro ni
There is one bright light, and with it a thousand souls.
miageru sora wo shinjiteru
Believe in the sky above his head,
michibiku hoshi wo higashi no takami ni sashishimesu yo
there putevodnaâ our star in the east, ee do not engage.
yume wa kono te de kanaeru
And their cherished dream in flesh forces.
Estelle eyes shed tears.
エステルの目から　涙がこぼれた
At the end of countless deaths and tragic death
無数の悲惨な死が積み重ねられた末に
it is a new birth.
一つの誕生が訪れた
Next time:. "The way out of the blood and sweat"
次回　汗血公路
Chapter XXV
And so the guy would be King.
少年は　そして王となる